Anmol Saxena

Cognitive Science - Machine Learning and Neural Computation

© Katy TX, 77494

Career Objective

Quality-oriented Cognitive Science major currently attending University of California - San Diego, with 3 years of work experience. Aiming to leverage a proven knowledge of machine learning, automation, and natural language processing to successfully fill this role at your company. Frequently praised as hardworking by my peers, I can be relied upon to help your company achieve its goals.

Experience

Research Assistant @ Security and Cryptography Lab

UC San Diego, La Jolla, CA / Jan 2022 - Current

- Designing and implementing program solutions for presented problems
- Working in a team to conduct a full end-to-end study

Instructional Apprentice

UC – San Diego, La Jolla, CA / Jan 2022 – March 2022

- Held office hours to help students
- Help design and grade test questions

Online Instructor

iD Tech, Katy, TX / Apr 2021 - Oct 2021

- Taught multiple week-long courses simultaneously
- Taught introductions to programming languages (Java, JavaScript, Python, C++)
- Incorporated visual design and in-game programming

Sales Intern

HighRadius, Houston, TX / Jun 2019 - Aug 2019

- Learned about the sales pipeline, marketing strategy, and high-level aspects of SaaS
- Developed marketing strategy that I presented to the Director of Marketing

Research and Projects

SpamStudy Used modified web scraper to obtain information about spam email for research purposes.

Tools: chrome driver, shell scripting, web design, JavaScript, Python

PreReq Used web scraper to obtain data from all course listings to provide an easy-access search bar.

Tools: crontab, web design, shell scripting, JavaScript, Python

NotionExt | Tools that interact with Notion, Apple Calendar, Apple Notes, and import/export with Notion.

Tools: crontab, Notion API, NodeJS, JavaScript, Python, AppleScript

ParkingSystem | Website for students to pay for and choose parking spots at Cinco Ranch High School.

Tools: PHP, MySQL, CSS, JavaScript

Education

University of California – San Diego

GPA: 3.5

Bachelor of Science (B.S.) Cognitive Science – Machine Learning and Neural Computation Expected graduation Sep 2022

Skills

Backend: Java, SQL, C, C++, Python, JavaScript

General Skills: Junit Testing, jQuery, ReactJS, NodeJS, HTML, CSS, PHP, Bash, Linux, Python

Certifications

- Machine Learning with Python
- Python for Data Science and AI
- Applied Data Science
- Databases and SQL for Data Science